To talk with your friends online, start a party.
Double-tap the Xbox button, go down to Parties,
and choose Start a party.
Right away you’re in a party of one.
The crown by your gamertag shows you’re the party leader.
Friends can now see in their Friends list
that you’re in a party, and can join you.
If you don’t want to allow others to join
without an invitation from you,
select Make the party invite-only.
The current setting is shown up at the top.
Also at the top there’s an icon that shows what microphone
your Xbox is using for chat, a headset or Kinect.
Choose Invite more to invite your friends.
Select who to invite, and then Send invite.
After your friends join the party, you can chat,
even if you’re all doing different things.
If you’re playing a multiplayer game when you start a party,
you can invite your friends right into game.
Just choose Invite to game before you send the invite.
Anyone can mute themselves or other people in the party,
and can send invites to their friends to join.
But only the party leader can remove people from the party.
When you get an invite to a party,
it pops up as a notification. To join right away,
press and hold the Xbox button on your controller briefly.
If you don’t join right away,
check your notifications for the invite.
Or look at your Friends list to see who’s in a party.
Select their gamertag to see who else is in the party, and to join.
Discover more! Get information and tips from Xbox Help.